Kristopher L. Lucas MT(ASCP)

Brookhaven, Ga Phone: (404) 550-5082 E-mail: klucas72@hotmail.com

QUALIFICATIONS

Bachelors of Science degrees in Medical Technology and Network Communications and Management with twenty years of laboratory and IT experience in diverse facilities. Expertise in technical and management in a diverse environment. Areas of expertise include:

Windows Server Administrator Cisco Routers and switches

Full Stack Web Development Linux Redhat Server Administrator

Languages include: CSS, HTML Javascript, Express JS, JSON

CERTIFICATION

National Registry

Project Management Certificate

Project Medium Society for Clinical Pathology #03628940

University of Georgia

July, 2017

Georgia Institute of Technology

July 2021

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

Network Administrator Maintained, monitored and performed administrative tasks for small

business Servers for clients in various environments. Knowledge of various transmission and routing protocols such as OSPF and RIP.

Software Implementation

Specialist/Consultant

Deployed and set up software database packages on customer

network. Performed customer oriented training after deployment and provided post installation support for any user questions or concerns

Full Stack Web Developer Created and developed web applications for public and private use.

Porfilio & Projects: https://klucas72.github.io/Portfolio/

Linkin Profile: www.linkedin.com/in/kristopher-lucas-1467355

GitHub Profile: https://github.com/klucas72

Project 1: https://klucas72.github.io/5-Day-forecast-application/

- •5 day forecast app using JavaScript, html, and CSS. Enter city name and you will receive current and 5 day forecast for that city
- •HTML was injected into framework with JavaScript

Project 2: https://kindred-app.herokuapp.com/

- •Social Media application focused on common interests in entertainment.
- •Worked with a team to create application.
- •Used HTML, CSS, JavaScript, REACT with Bootstrap framework

HISTORY

Software Systems Technical Immucor, Inc.

2013 to present

Specialist

Accomplishments:

- Analyzed and troubleshot MiaFora Servers for configuration network communications issues. Worked with international customers resolving their issues.
- Installed software using SQL for database, IIS, Redhat OS configurations
- Trained customers on the use and maintenance of LIS interface software.
- Project manager for setting up and installing software database package on customer networks.
- Setup and configured instrument interfaces (LIS) for lab instruments to talk to customer laboratory information systems.

Network Administrator

Alpha Group/Altair Advanced Ind. 2012 to 2013 *Accomplishments:*

- administered domain policies, set permissions, roles, and access to various network resources. Installed complete wireless network for customers.
- Maintained and troubleshot network traffic issues for the domain as well as set up and maintained network servers.

Network Admin/Engineer

Toph Tech Consulting *Accomplishments:*

2011 to present

- administered domain policies, set permissions, roles, and access to various network resources. Installed complete wireless network for organization.
- Maintained and troubleshot network traffic issues for the domain as well as set up and maintained network servers.

EDUCATION

Network Communications and Management Medical Technology Project Management Certificate Full Stack Web Development Certificate DeVry University, Atlanta, Ga 2007-2012 Indiana State University, Terre Haute, IN 1991–1995 University of Georgia July, 2017 Georgia Institute of Technology July 2021